<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>theGreatWhiteShark</title>
    <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on theGreatWhiteShark</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 13:49:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Encryption, password management, and backups in Linux</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/encryption-and-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 13:49:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/encryption-and-backup/</guid>
      <description>Since at least the revelations of Edward Snowden we know that encryption is not just an important but also a quite pressing issue. But, unfortunately, there is no one size fits all algorithm that works with all kinds of data and communication protocols. We are therefore bound to at least peek into different topics of this rather complex field. But don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid. I wrote this introduction with people at a beginner level in Linux in mind and won&amp;rsquo;t touch a single bit of mathematical theory on encryption in here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecmwf_retrieve</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/ecmwf_retrieve/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 12:41:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/ecmwf_retrieve/</guid>
      <description>In the last post about the dwd2r R package I showed you how to retrieve large amount of observational data from within Germany. This is one of the highest quality data sets available and certainly a very nice starting point for your climatological analysis. But it only covers Germany. If you intend to analysis data from another location on the globe, hopefully the government of the corresponding country shares their data with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dwd2r</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/dwd2r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 12:44:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/dwd2r/</guid>
      <description>The German weather service (DWD) provides a large set of climatological data under the following terms of use. This is an awesome starting point for data-driven software or research. But, as usual, it is only the starting point. The observational data itself is provided for all individual stations in separate files and split into the most recent and a historical part. This is of course quite convenient in case you want to update your data sets but it&amp;rsquo;s up to the user to combine both parts for each and every station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lightning-keymap-mode</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/lightning-keymap-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/lightning-keymap-mode/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it, the navigation in plain Emacs is not that sophisticated. Actually, it&amp;rsquo;s almost unusable. The approach of Evil-mode, on the other hand, is not a bad idea but I never really liked the way VI is doing things. Context switches are just not my style. I definitely prefer the key combination approach of Emacs.
So what can be done instead? Well, why not creating a mixture of both worlds?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Wordpress to Github Pages&#43;Hugo</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/moving-to-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 22:27:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/moving-to-github/</guid>
      <description>I moved my blog from Wordpress to Github Pages.
In addition, I also decided to split the blog in three different parts. Art, coding, and music are just a little too diverse and I intend to do further posts in all of these subjects.
You can find the blogs via the following links
 music blog coding blog overall blog  Motivation First of all, I have to say: I had a nice time on Wordpress and it was a great place to start my blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data science</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 11:58:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacks</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 11:58:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/hacks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 17:39:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a PhD student in physics, a passionated programmer, a vehement open-source user, a picky musician, and an aspiring artist.
In this blog I want to share my experiences, present the solutions I found to encountered problems, and maybe help some other people out there facing similar challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climex</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/climex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/climex/</guid>
      <description>The Climex app is my longest and most comprehensive endeavor in the realm of programming and software development up to now. It started as a couple of wrapper functions in the beginning of my PhD in 2015 and is still (at the time of writing) under active development.
In this post I won&amp;rsquo;t explain the motivation and basics of the extreme value analysis (EVA), which can be found in the vignettes of the package, but its basic handling and the improvements it introduces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A data scientist’s view on the election for the Bundestag Pt. II</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-ii/</guid>
      <description>The internal representation of spatial objects in R is quite complicated. You might already experienced this while searching for neat ways to plot maps of your data online. When everything you know consists of data.frames, lists, strings, and factors, you most probably had a hard time dealing with the answers presented there. But this is about to change. Once introduced to their representation, spatial objects and the corresponding plotting routines become as simple and straight forward as any other R objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A data scientist’s view on the election for the Bundestag Pt. I</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-i/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to loads of publicly available data it&amp;rsquo;s possible to get further insight into the past and current state of the world, as well as possible future perspectives. May it be for professional reasons as a data scientist or just out of pure curiosity, using modern statistical computer languages all of us are capable of obtaining those insights.
Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s often said that as a data scientist you spend 80% of your time not on your analysis but on the data itself: 40% on finding the right data and 40% on cleaning it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wxArt</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/wxart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 17:55:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/wxart/</guid>
      <description>The paper A Neural Algorithm of Artistic Style by Leon A. Gatys, Alexander S. Ecker, and Matthias Bethge in 2015 was a game changer. It was not just one of the major sparks to light up the interest in deep learning in general, it also was one of the reasons Stephan and I started a reading group on machine learning back in the beginning of 2016. And we are still committed to it and meet at an almost weekly basis at time of writing (24.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mensacard Hack Pt. III</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/hacks/mensacard-pt-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/hacks/mensacard-pt-iii/</guid>
      <description>To make a long story short, it&amp;rsquo;s not trivial to access the content of the Mensacard and I didn&amp;rsquo;t managed to do it with the technology I had at hand.
But if you ever wanted to develop code for your Arduino in Emacs instead of the Arduino IDE, you will find a more or less comprehensive guide to do so in here.
The technology I used:
 Acer Aspire S3 running Ubuntu 16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much computer skills does a physicist need?</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/how-much-computer-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/how-much-computer-skills/</guid>
      <description>Computational skills are something almost every scientist has to offer nowadays. But unfortunately the least of us are actually trained in it. So most colleges (including me) took the autodidactic approach, a long road full of detours and wasted effort.
For those of you who are already decent programmers but did not dived into a lot of languages and tools, I try to compile a summary of all the essential stuff I tried during my PhD in this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mensacard Hack Pt. II</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/hacks/mensacard-pt-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/hacks/mensacard-pt-ii/</guid>
      <description>Why I tried using Ionic. The main reason for me to do this project is to acquire all necessary skills to quickly prototype an Android app.
It happened a couple of times already that I had a very nice idea or even a more or less elaborate roadmap to a product but in the end decided to file it away due to the gigantic overhead of app development. I really dislike doing this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mensacard Hack Pt. I</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/hacks/mensacard-pt-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/hacks/mensacard-pt-i/</guid>
      <description>In the first part of the series we will do the whole setup for the development environment and all the code is available on my Github page.
Introduction Since NFC and RFID is imho a quite nice way to communicate with things you build which do not have any power supply I wanted to dive into this topic since quite a while. And be honest: who wants to have cables all over the place when you also could do it without?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vasp2R</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/vasp2r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/vasp2r/</guid>
      <description>It is about my endeavors to create some neat plots of the results obtained using the proprietary DFT program VASP one and a half years ago. Since these files are usually pretty big it is important for your plotting script to rely on compiled C, C++ or Fortran code under the hood of a high level language like R or python. And you definitely want to have one of the latter ones for creating you plots since it is way more easy and beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which part of town fits me best?</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/stadtteilsuchedd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 16:16:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/stadtteilsuchedd/</guid>
      <description>It was in mid autumn when I heard there will be a local version of the Chaos Computer Congress, the annual conference of the German hacker association Chaos Computer Club, called Datenspuren in the city of Dresden. Since I was living in Dresden back then, my attendance was somewhat mandatory. But when I check the program one day in advance I saw something even better: There would be a hackathon organized by the city of Dresden and they would award prices worth of 7000€ in total.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>