<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on theGreatWhiteShark</title>
    <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on theGreatWhiteShark</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 22:27:35 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Wordpress to Github Pages&#43;Hugo</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/life-beyond-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 22:27:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/life-beyond-google/</guid>
      <description>I moved my blog from Wordpress to Github Pages.
In addition, I also decided to split the blog in three different parts. Art, coding, and music are just a little too diverse and I intend to do further posts in all of these subjects.
You can find the blogs via the following links
 music blog coding blog overall blog  Motivation First of all, I have to say: I had a nice time on Wordpress and it was a great place to start my blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much computer skills does a physicist need?</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/how-much-computer-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/how-much-computer-skills/</guid>
      <description>Computational skills are something almost every scientist has to offer nowadays. But unfortunately the least of us are actually trained in it. So most colleges (including me) took the autodidactic approach, a long road full of detours and wasted effort.
For those of you who are already decent programmers but did not dived into a lot of languages and tools, I try to compile a summary of all the essential stuff I tried during my PhD in this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vasp2R</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/vasp2r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/vasp2r/</guid>
      <description>It is about my endeavors to create some neat plots of the results obtained using the proprietary DFT program VASP one and a half years ago. Since these files are usually pretty big it is important for your plotting script to rely on compiled C, C++ or Fortran code under the hood of a high level language like R or python. And you definitely want to have one of the latter ones for creating you plots since it is way more easy and beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>