<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data-science on theGreatWhiteShark</title>
    <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data-science on theGreatWhiteShark</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 20:02:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A data scientist’s view on the election for the Bundestag Pt. II</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-ii/</guid>
      <description>The internal representation of spatial objects in R is quite complicated. You might already experienced this while searching for neat ways to plot maps of your data online. When everything you know consists of data.frames, lists, strings, and factors, you most probably had a hard time dealing with the answers presented there. But this is about to change. Once introduced to their representation, spatial objects and the corresponding plotting routines become as simple and straight forward as any other R objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A data scientist’s view on the election for the Bundestag Pt. I</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-i/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to loads of publicly available data it&amp;rsquo;s possible to get further insight into the past and current state of the world, as well as possible future perspectives. May it be for professional reasons as a data scientist or just out of pure curiosity, using modern statistical computer languages all of us are capable of obtaining those insights.
Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s often said that as a data scientist you spend 80% of your time not on your analysis but on the data itself: 40% on finding the right data and 40% on cleaning it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>