<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on theGreatWhiteShark</title>
    <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on theGreatWhiteShark</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 13:49:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Encryption, password management, and backups in Linux</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/encryption-and-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 13:49:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/encryption-and-backup/</guid>
      <description>Since at least the revelations of Edward Snowden we know that encryption is not just an important but also a quite pressing issue. But, unfortunately, there is no one size fits all algorithm that works with all kinds of data and communication protocols. We are therefore bound to at least peek into different topics of this rather complex field. But don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid. I wrote this introduction with people at a beginner level in Linux in mind and won&amp;rsquo;t touch a single bit of mathematical theory on encryption in here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecmwf_retrieve</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/ecmwf_retrieve/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 12:41:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/ecmwf_retrieve/</guid>
      <description>In the last post about the dwd2r R package I showed you how to retrieve large amount of observational data from within Germany. This is one of the highest quality data sets available and certainly a very nice starting point for your climatological analysis. But it only covers Germany. If you intend to analysis data from another location on the globe, hopefully the government of the corresponding country shares their data with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dwd2r</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/dwd2r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 12:44:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/dwd2r/</guid>
      <description>The German weather service (DWD) provides a large set of climatological data under the following terms of use. This is an awesome starting point for data-driven software or research. But, as usual, it is only the starting point. The observational data itself is provided for all individual stations in separate files and split into the most recent and a historical part. This is of course quite convenient in case you want to update your data sets but it&amp;rsquo;s up to the user to combine both parts for each and every station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A data scientist’s view on the election for the Bundestag Pt. I</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-i/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to loads of publicly available data it&amp;rsquo;s possible to get further insight into the past and current state of the world, as well as possible future perspectives. May it be for professional reasons as a data scientist or just out of pure curiosity, using modern statistical computer languages all of us are capable of obtaining those insights.
Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s often said that as a data scientist you spend 80% of your time not on your analysis but on the data itself: 40% on finding the right data and 40% on cleaning it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>