<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on theGreatWhiteShark</title>
    <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on theGreatWhiteShark</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 20:02:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Climex</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/climex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/climex/</guid>
      <description>The Climex app is my longest and most comprehensive endeavor in the realm of programming and software development up to now. It started as a couple of wrapper functions in the beginning of my PhD in 2015 and is still under active development.
In this post I won&amp;rsquo;t explain the motivation and basics of the extreme value analysis (EVA). But I intend to do a separate post dedicated to this topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A data scientist’s view on the election for the Bundestag Pt. II</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-ii/</guid>
      <description>The internal representation of spatial objects in R is quite complicated. You might already experienced this while searching for neat ways to plot maps of your data online. When everything you know consists of data.frames, lists, strings, and factors, you most probably had a hard time dealing with the answers presented there. But this is about to change. Once introduced to their representation, spatial objects and the corresponding plotting routines become as simple and straight forward as any other R objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A data scientist’s view on the election for the Bundestag Pt. I</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/bundestagswahl-pt-i/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to loads of publicly available data it&amp;rsquo;s possible to get further insight into the past and current state of the world, as well as possible future perspectives. May it be for professional reasons as a data scientist or just out of pure curiosity, using modern statistical computer languages all of us are capable of obtaining those insights.
Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s often said that as a data scientist you spend 80% of your time not on your analysis but on the data itself: 40% on finding the right data and 40% on cleaning it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much computer skills does a physicist need?</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/how-much-computer-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/how-much-computer-skills/</guid>
      <description>Computational skills are something almost every scientist has to offer nowadays. But unfortunately the least of us are actually trained in it. So most colleges (including me) took the autodidactic approach, a long road full of detours and wasted effort.
For those of you who are already decent programmers but did not dived into a lot of languages and tools, I try to compile a summary of all the essential stuff I tried during my PhD in this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vasp2R</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/vasp2r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 20:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/vasp2r/</guid>
      <description>It is about my endeavors to create some neat plots of the results obtained using the proprietary DFT program VASP one and a half years ago. Since these files are usually pretty big it is important for your plotting script to rely on compiled C, C++ or Fortran code under the hood of a high level language like R or python. And you definitely want to have one of the latter ones for creating you plots since it is way more easy and beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which part of town fits me best?</title>
      <link>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/stadtteilsuchedd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 16:16:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thegreatwhiteshark.github.io/thegreatwhiteshark.coding.io/data-science/stadtteilsuchedd/</guid>
      <description>It was in mid autumn when I heard there will be a local version of the Chaos Computer Congress, the annual conference of the German hacker association Chaos Computer Club, called Datenspuren in the city of Dresden. Since I was living in Dresden back then, my attendance was somewhat mandatory. But when I check the program one day in advance I saw something even better: There would be a hackathon organized by the city of Dresden and they would award prices worth of 7000€ in total.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>